This year... This summer, where shall we go?
I want to hit a summer festival with Tani-kun!
The fireworks show the next town over?
I do wanna see fireworks,
but the show'll probably be crowded,
so maybe we should go to the local
summer festival that's on the same day.
Does that mean wearing a yukata?
Tani-kun in a yukata?!
I wanna see that,
but I don't want anyone else to!
No, I meant you, Suzuki.
Wait, inviting Tani-kun comes first!
Term exams come before that, you know?
YOU AND I ARE POLAR OPPOSITES
All right, what we covered today
will be on the exam.
Every person has a sixth sense.
The light of a certain star destroys
the minds of young children.
Aside from death, it is the fourth end!
End-of-term exams.
The only one who remembers
their existence now is me, and—
The text demons still live.
Say, did you know that "bibimbap" is actually
pronounced more like "pibimpap"?
Bibimbap
Pibimpap
Don't run from reality.
Hey, did you know that?
Don't drag Tani-kun into this.
Taki-kun, how have you said it up to now?
Bibimbap.
Heh
See?
What do you mean, "See?"
"Pap" means "rice," so apparently
"pibimpap" is closer to the real pronunciation.
Pap
Pibimpap
Huh.
We get it. Now please face facts.
Wait, what? But exams aren't now, right?
We'll be fine!
Hey!
Ho! Ho!
The ones who really shouldn't
shrug the exams off definitely are.
Ho!
Hey!
Don't ask to copy my notes
right before exams again, okay?
What?!
Don't "What?!" me!
If you're gonna copy them, do it now.
That's it! Today, we're having a study session!
For real?
Wha?
Speaking of which, where's Taira?
I think he said something about
training at his part-time job.
Oh!
Hey, Tani! You in on this study session?
What?
No.
Okay.
Yeah, he's not worried at all.
More like Tani-kun doesn't see
any merit in studying with us.
No, you've got it all wrong.
He has to work in the library after this.
Oh, that's what he meant.
No.
How were we supposed to know that?
He's way too short on words.
Hey, hang on. I just realized
something awesome!
Oh! You, too?
Fully Equipped Air Conditioning
(Read: The Library)
The library!
All right, start by copying my notes.
Suzuki, your notebooks are super flashy!
World History
Doesn't look like you do much studying.
High School
World History
As long as the contents are solid, it's fine!
Crap, did we have a lecture on this?
I can't remember, even with the notes!
You must've been asleep. You gonna be okay?
Well, you know, if things get bad,
I'll just open the eighth gate.
Eight Inner Gates
That makes this grave business.
All right!
I'm all done.
All you did was copy my notes. Both of you.
If I keep studying like this, an average
score of sixty won't be just a dream.
Yeah...
I don't understand the homework.
What's the answer to this?
Give it a little thought for yourself!
Meanie.
Tani, tell me the answer!
Me, too!
Hey, stop that!
And so, X equals 2.
Did you get that?
Oh, I see now!
Perfect.
Okay, Tani! Why don't you come with us
and we'll all go to TokyoU?
You're jumping way too far ahead.
Then where do we stand now?
You're putting me in a tough spot.
You saying we have so much potential
for growth that you can't calculate it?
Why are you smiling like that?
Oh, it's nothing!
It's just that seeing the person I love
and my friends getting closer
makes me pretty... happy?
Like, I get all fidgety.
Hm, I think I understand a little.
We started out in separate groups,
but now the barriers are vanishing, right?
Yeah, that's it!
I have a feeling I'll get into TokyoU.
Yeah, me too.
No, I think it'll be me.
Hey, Tani-kun, what do you think?
Do you think I can make friends with him?
I'm sure you can, Sato!
After all, you and Tani-kun are kind of alike.
What?
Okay, time to go home! Home time!
Thanks to Tani-kun, I comprehend
everything in the world.
That's great!
We were talking about how
I'm gonna aim for TokyoU.
Yeah, you're jumping way too far ahead.
Suzuki, that's the exact same quip
Tani-kun used!
Are your brains synced or what?
What? That would be shameless of me!
Would it?
Honestly!
Yamada, don't you get it yet?
Hey, she's running away.
That's a run of embarrassment.
Honestly! I mean, really! Honestly!
Hey, Tani, what time do you get off work?
You sound like a crappy customer
asking when his shift is over.
Yay!
We're done! All done!
I feel so light and free!
Tani-kun.
Sorry for bothering you in there.
It's fine. People don't usually come in
after school, so this was fun.
That was fun?
Hey, let's grab something
to eat before we go home!
What're you in the mood for?
Bibimbap!
Pibimpap.
Sounds good!
Let's go! Let's go!
"Bap"?
Tani-kun, you said "pap"
like you're supposed to!
Suzuki-san, you're the one
who told me that was correct.
Yeah, but I mean...
"Bibimbap" is easier to say, isn't it?
Pibimpap
X
Bibimbap
Go! Bibimbap! Go!
Go, go!
I wanna eat some bibimbap!
Suzuki can be like that sometimes.
Hang in there, Tani-kun.
Yeah.
Hey, what's this?
Are you two whispering about me?
Where do you get that confidence?
Hey! We're gonna leave you behind!
Are you up for bibimbap-ing or not?
I am, I am! I'm so up for bimbap-ing!
Bibim-don
Meal ticket
Bibim style
I wish we could've gotten the stone pot kind.
Yup. This is good.
Right?
Don't beg for luxuries.
Either kind works...
Sometimes, I get a little excited.
*Suzuki
Like when...
Popuri
GRAND OPENING SALE
First 3 days only
a convenience store opens near my house.
This is today!
I'm making a quick trip to the store!
I'm in the mood for ice cream
after dinner this time of year
-S
Oh, wait!
Will you buy some toilet paper for me?
What? That's cheaper at the supermarket.
Well, we only have a third of a roll left.
That is a problem.
Wait, you're going out like that?
So much for your pride as a woman.
You need an exorcist?
Cigarettes
Grab some Luckys for me.
I'm not buying those!
I mean, he did have a point. If you
asked if I'd go see Tani-kun like this...
that'd be a hard no.
Popuri
Oh, hey.
Huh?
We had the
same thought
For real? What kind of coincidence is this?
Did you bring the flier and coupons?
You bet I did!
Hey, those gym shorts
are from middle school.
You can't wear those out of the house.
What about your fancy
pretend-loungewear-for-going-out track pants?
You should quit while you're ahead.
Oh, shut up.
Hey! Taira's working here!
Don't show up all excited on our first day.
You know I would.
Say, Taira, you don't live
around here, do you?
Somewhere near school
is easier on weekdays, y'know?
Plus, I'd see everyone from
middle school near my house.
Huh? What's wrong with having
your friends come see you at work?
As you may inconvenience other customers,
could I ask you to hurry up
with your shopping and leave?
And suddenly he's got his work face on.
Somehow...
Ummm...
having a guy my own age working the register
makes it embarrassing to buy toilet paper.
You've got more to be embarrassed about.
I could not care less about your embarrassment.
See you later!
I'll come to print tickets and pick up
stuff shipped from flea markets!
Don't increase my workload!
Gapacho's recommendation is good.
Not bad, Gapacho.
Did it rain today?
Maybe for a second this evening?
It stopped right away, though.
Yeah? I thought so.
You get this nice smell after it rains.
Sorry. I dunno what you mean.
Um, it's like plants and the earth...
Sorry. Please just forget it.
A Cub motorcycle shifting gears?
Is it the police?
What?
They're coming this way!
Make a break for it! Run!
Huh?
Nabe!
What? What're you doing here?
I was out on my bike and took a detour.
You get a nice wind on this road here.
The one most likely to get
nabbed by the cops is here.
I thought, "Ugh. There's a delinquent
couple hanging out here. This is the pits."
I'm glad it was just you two,
Suzuki and Yamada.
My friend saw me and thought,
"This is the pits."
Man, Suzuki, it takes guts
to go out like that, doesn't it?
Huh? This is my neighborhood,
so it's fine, right?
Middle school gym shorts are a bad sign.
I wonder what Tani-kun
would think if he saw this.
What? Not happening!
I'd never let him see me like this.
It's not that different from your usual.
It most certainly is!
But I've got nothing to worry about.
Tani-kun would never go out to the
convenience store at this time of night.
Huh? Suzuki-san?
And... Yamada-kun and Watanabe-san, too.
You noticed
Too slow.
Tani! Why are you wandering
around at this time of night?
You must be a hoodlum! A hoodlum!
Don't close your eyes to your own faults.
Heading home from cram school...
Why did Suzuki-san disappear?
Well... don't let it bother you.
Just go and finish your shopping.
Suzuki was never here.
What?
You must have something to say.
Not getting teased leads
to its own kind of anxiety
Okay! Run while you have the chance!
And make sure you explain yourself later, okay?
Thank you both.
Hey! Gimme my helmet back!
I'm sorry, Tani-kun!
I want to be myself with you,
but that doesn't mean I can
show you every little thing!
If I did and it disillusioned you...
I don't want that!
Okay! Now that I've run this far,
like Achilles and the tortoise...
Suzuki-san.
A-Achilles...
Why are you running away?
B-Because...
But none of that bothers me.
Even if it doesn't seem like it's
a big deal from your perspective,
it's a vibes problem for me.
Vibes?
Even though you don't care with Yamada-kun?
Huh?
Well, I mean, he's just Yamada.
I've known him since middle school,
so this is kind of small potatoes.
What about Taira-kun and Watanabe-san?
Huh? Nabe and I have been together
since our first year of high school,
and Taira is... Well, he's Taira.
Dismissed
I see.
Huh?
Tani-kun, you seem blatantly upset right now.
I'm understanding more and more...
I won't hear it from
someone who blatantly ran.
Oh, boldly spoken.
It's just...
I'm jealous of how long Yamada-kun
and the others have known you.
Tani-kun...
Imagine there's some food here.
Now, let's say we have a slapped-together
dish on a random plate
and a nicely presented one on a cute plate.
Even if they both taste the same,
Tani-kun, I want to give you the nice one.
I want to show myself off!
Basically, that's it!
No matter how it's presented,
if it's a dish I like, then I'm not
concerned about the rest.
Huh?
Wait, that's problematic.
Hang on...
What?
When I've got a pretty dish on a pretty plate,
hearing stuff like "I like how this looks" or
"this plating is nice" get me pumped up.
Pumped up?
You mean the vibes?
Yeah, the vibes!
Tani-kun.
Let me ride on the back.
Sure.
But I might not be very good at this.
It's fine! Don't worry!
It's so nice and cool!
Hey, you know...
You know how summer nights have this
exquisite kind of... mood? Atmosphere?
Isn't it kind of thrilling?
Yeah, it is.
Also, this...
this smell you get after the rain.
I love that.
Yeah.
I love it, too.
Hey, Suzuki's little sister!
Don't play around out here at night! Go home!
Will do!
Why do the police know her on sight?
Let's ride vehicles
correctly and safely, okay?
I can't wait for our summer festival date!
Everyone safely escaped remedial lessons
Yay
Safe
Yeah
You sure are cheerful
now that exams are over.
And you decided to go
to the little festival after all.
Yeah! If we went to fireworks show...
We'd have to fight for a spot and there's
a big wait. Then once it's over,
you have an unmoving line back
to the station. Thinking of all that...
Hard facts.
If I wore a yukata, do you think
I'd be trying too hard?
Huh? Why would you think that?
Wearing one's the way to go!
Since there's no guarantee
you'll be dating next year!
Hey!
How could you say that?!
I'm just saying that it's best
to keep these things in mind.
Huh?! Huh?! Huh?! Huh?! Huh?!
You mean she shouldn't get complacent
or hold back in their relationship.
Exactly!
I see.
Just don't get all giddy like a girl
in one of those sickeningly sweet couples.
Never gonna happen.
Koneko-machi Bulletin Board
Summer Festival
Festival
Koneko-machi Summer Festival
So excited
Read
I'll be there soon!
So excited
Read
I'll be there soon!
I'm in front of the statue
Roger that!
Read
Roger
What should I do? Do I look weird?
Should I have gotten
my hair done at the salon?
How does everyone fit everything into these
tiny drawstring bags? Are they geniuses?
Are foam sandals heretical?
I'm sweating so much, my makeup
might already be melting off!
Oh, I'm so nervous!
Nervous
Sweating
Tani-kun!
Sorry to keep you waiting.
You surprised me.
Um... do I look weird?
No.
You're beautiful.
BEAUTIFUL
Before this moment,
I've barely cleared the "cute" bar,
Suzuki, that's so cute!
Ha ha, you're cute!
*Being teased
but have I ever been called "beautiful"?
This kind of thing's
happened, though
Beautifully
done
Right?
W-Welp, shall we go crazy at the festival?!
There's no need to go crazy, is there?
They've got all your
festival sounds and smells!
Right?
How about we take a quick look
around and decide what to buy?
If you want anything, speak up, okay?
Suzuki-san, behind you!
Oh, I'm so sorry!
No, it's fine.
That was close.
There are so many people that
we'll have to be careful, right?
Yeah, that's true.
What is it?
It's sort of... like we're a couple.
HAPPY
"Like a couple"?
This is bad! I'm totally
gonna end up all giddy!
I see him every day at school,
Only strangers around
but that's exactly what makes
this situation so much fun!
Just the two of us out together
Put extra effort into this outfit
Important
Okonomiyaki
Yakisoba
Granted...
Want to split it?
It's best not to get too carried away, right?
Heck yeah!
This is so good!
That said...
I can't help myself!
Topped with every flavor of syrup
Use as much syrup
as you want
Yay!
Shaved Ice
At a time like this,
it's totally impossible not to be giddy!
Koneko-machi Festival
Wow, amazing!
Super Ball
Get this many, keep this many
1-10 balls: 1 ball
11-20 balls: 2 balls
21 or more: 3 balls
Wordless
pressure
Two balls acquired!
Are you sure you want to give me one?
Yes. Actually, I'd give you both of them.
No, you can't do that.
Should you need anything to wipe your hands,
please don't hesitate to ask.
You're so prepared.
I ran all kinds of simulations!
List of Handy Stuff to Have
-Tissues
-Wet Towelettes
-Handkerchief/Towel
-Electric fan/Folding fan
-Bandages
-Etc.
Wait, would not saying that have
made me seem more smart and chic?
Thank you.
I'm so happy.
Taku-chan!
Yes?
The way they're flirting is utterly shameless!
Whoa! That's insane!
When your giddy meter maxes out,
is that what you turn into?
But the scary thing is...
there's a part of me that kind of
understands how they feel.
When my boyfriend wasn't around,
I was weirdly confident
I wouldn't get so giddy
that I'd lose sight of my surroundings.
And yet, what was I like today?
What do I do? All of a sudden,
I'm starting to feel super embarrassed!
Tani-kun...
Do you maybe need to get home?
Suzuki-san, do you mind a little walk?
Huh?
Wow! This is the first time I've come this way!
We keep climbing higher and higher.
I wonder where he's taking me.
Don't tell me! A nightscape?
We're here.
There's a lot of people here.
Yeah.
Wow!
Kinda iffy.
What do I do? If I don't know what he's
thinking, it makes it harder to react.
Hey! Aren't the fireworks starting yet?
It's almost time. Just wait.
Huh?
Wh-What?!
The fireworks from the show we didn't go to!
You can see them from here?!
They're far away, though.
That's fine! Totally fine!
Tani-kun, thank you.
I wonder if I can capture them.
They're far, so I doubt it.
Yeah, you're right.
I guess I'll just burn them into my eyeballs.
That was clo—
That was close!
I thought we were gonna kiss!
Wait. That'd be fine, right?
If we did.
Actually, I totally want to.
Suzuki-san.
Huh?
Next time, let's get even closer.
Next time? Even closer?
To what?
The fireworks show.
They'll have it next year too, right?
Over there.
Let's go! Definitely!
In Tani-kun's idea of "next year,"
I'm there!
Have fun at the festival?
It was a total win.
What'd you win at?